(upbeat music)
- Hello everyone, welcome to another
lesson at English Pod, my name is Marco.
- My name is Catherine, so Marco,
what are we talking about today?
- Today we're gonna be
talking about a popular
topic all over the world,
and that is smoking.
- Well, not so popular in the
States right now, to be honest.
- Well, that's the thing in
every country in the world.
Now they are becoming
more strict on smoking
and where you can smoke, so it's becoming
very difficult for smokers nowadays.
- Well, it's a good reason to want to quit.
- And that's what we're gonna be
talking about today is quitting smoking.
- Well, before we get going, we
do have a really important phrase
that we should preview in
today's vocabulary preview.
- Very cabaret-y preview.
- All right, so on vocabulary preview,
we're gonna take a look at
this word, pack of smokes.
- Pack of smokes, a pack of smokes.
- So smokes is a word for cigarettes,
it's the same thing, smokes or cigarettes.
- Right, but a pack is like 20 cigarettes.
- It's a box of cigarettes,
you buy them in a pack.
You don't just buy one at a time.
So, again, the phrase is pack of smokes.
- Pack of smokes.
So why don't we listen
to our dialogue for the
first time and see what's
going on with this smoker?
(upbeat music)
- Oh, it smells like an ashtrane here.
- Hi honey, what's wrong?
Why do you have that look on your face?
- What's wrong?
I thought we agreed you
were gonna quit smoking.
- No, I said I was gonna cut
down, which is very different.
You can't just expect me
to go cold turkey overnight.
- Look, there are other ways to quit.
You can try the nicotine
patch or nicotine chewing gum.
We spend a fortune on cigarettes every
month, and now laws are cracking down
and not allowing smoking
in any public place.
- It's not like you can
just light up like the form.
- I know, I know, I really am trying,
but I don't have the
willpower to just quit.
I can't fight with the
urge to reach for my pack
of smokes in the morning
with coffee or after lunch.
Please understand.
- Fine, I wanted a boss.
(upbeat music)
- Sorry, I just smoked a pack of sick.
(laughing)
- You do smoked, don't you?
- Well, we'll talk about that later.
- All right, so it is a
little bit extreme though.
I mean, he's divorcing
her 'cause she won't quit.
- Well, some people
really are health conscious
and are afraid of the
negative side of smoking,
which has a lot of
health side effects.
- Yeah.
- Well, as he was complaining
about all the negative
effects and the negative
aspects of smoking,
he did mention both of them
mentioned a lot of great words
and phrases, so why don't we take a
look at them now in language takeaway.
- Language takeaway.
Well, this first word is a
word that's very important
for any smoker who
goes to a bar or restaurant
and needs to put the
ash somewhere, right?
So when you smoke, there's
some ash, there's some messy
dirty stuff and you need
an ash tray to collect it.
- An ash tray.
- So an ash tray is something
that's usually round or square
and you put it on a table
and it's just very helpful
to keep the house
clean or restaurant clean.
- So if you're in a restaurant, you
say, hey, can I have an ash tray, please?
- So the residue or the stuff
that when you're smoking,
it comes out the gray, I don't
know, like dust, it's called ash.
- Right, and this is a
tray, but the complaint
here is it smells like
an ash tray in here.
That means it smells
really, really bad in here.
- Yeah, it smells like cigarettes.
- Yeah, so that word again is ash tray.
- Ash tray, all right.
- Well, and the guy was
complaining and he said,
well, I thought you
were gonna quit smoking
and she said, no, no, I said
I was going to cut down.
- She says it's very different
from quitting smoking.
So Marco, maybe we should
talk about how cutting down
and quitting are different.
- All right, so if I say
I'm gonna cut down
on smoking, it's just
I'm gonna smoke less.
Okay, so let's take an example.
I smoke 10 cigarettes a
day, but I wanna cut down.
How many should I smoke later?
Maybe like two or three?
- Three, two or three.
- Instead of quitting, so if you
quit smoking, that would mean zero.
- Zero cigarettes, no smoking anymore.
- Right.
- All right, so you can also cut
down on carbs, like carbohydrates.
So some people who cut
down on carbs eat less bread.
They don't eat any pasta.
So these are really good ways of trying
to talk about dieting as well as smoking.
- Right, and I think we
have a couple of examples
of other ways we can
use this phrase, cut down.
So let's listen to them now.
- Example one.
- Our company has decided
to cut down our workloads.
So from now on, we leave at 3 p.m.
every Friday.
- Example two.
You should really cut down
on the amount of salt you eat.
It's not good for you.
- Example three.
- My doctor told me I need to cut down on
fatty foods because of my heart condition.
- And when you want to smoke a cigarette,
you have to do something
first with some fires.
We call this lighting up to light up.
So lighting up, it doesn't
mean turning on the light.
It actually means using a lighter
or some fire to start your cigarette.
- Right, so you want to light up
with the lighter matches
or some sort of fire.
- The man says, the husband says, it's
not like you can just light up like before.
That means it's not like you
can just smoke like before.
So in some cases, light up
means to smoke a cigarette.
We're in a movie theater
and someone lights a
cigarette and I say, oh,
you can't light up in here.
- Right, so you can't smoke in here.
- You can't smoke it.
- It's another way of saying smoking.
Very good.
And she was explaining how
difficult it is and she's trying to quit.
But she said I don't have
the willpower to just quit.
Ooh, willpower.
So this is an important word, willpower.
You think of the main
part of this word as will.
That means the desire to do something.
You want to do something.
- So if I have willpower,
I have strong willpower.
What am I saying?
- You're saying that you can make a
decision and you can follow your decision.
So I decide not to eat cake.
I have very strong willpower.
So I never eat cake.
If I don't have strong willpower,
maybe I sometimes, secretly eat cake
in the middle of the
night from my refrigerator.
So that happens, right?
Sometimes you don't have
strong enough willpower
so you kind of eat
a little bit of cake.
I don't know what he's watching.
- Exactly.
And you can have willpower
about lots of different things.
So this is a great word again to use
when you're talking about
dieting or smoking or drinking.
- Any type of maybe temptation.
- Exactly.
- All right.
And well, she said she had this
urge to reach for her pack of smokes.
- Ooh, urge is another good one.
It's very similar to willpower.
But an urge is kind of like a physical
feeling that makes you want to do something.
- So you have like this strong desire.
- So I have the urge to go swimming today.
I don't know why, but I really want to.
- All right, you have an urge.
Interesting word.
- Pregnant women often
have these kinds of things too.
I have the urge to do something.
We also call them cravings.
- Oh cravings are urge to do something.
All right, interesting.
So you're taking a look
at these five great words
and I think we should
listen to our dialogue again.
We're gonna slow it down just a little bit
and then we'll come
back and talk some more.
(upbeat music)
- Oh, it smells like an ashtray in here.
- Hi, honey.
What's wrong?
Why do you have that look on your face?
- What's wrong?
I thought we agreed that
you were gonna quit smoking.
- No.
I said I was going to cut
down, which is very different.
You can't just expect me
to go cold turkey overnight.
- Look, there are other ways to quit.
You can try the nicotine
patch or nicotine chewing gum.
We spend a fortune on cigarettes every
month and now laws are cracking down
and not allowing smoking
in any public place.
It's not like you can
just light up like before.
- I know, I know, I really am trying,
but I don't have the
willpower to just quit.
I can't fight with the urge
to reach for my pack of
smokes in the morning
with coffee or after lunch.
Please understand.
- Fine, I want a divorce.
- And we are back, so we
have a great part of our show.
We like to talk about some
phrases that help you attain fluency.
That means sounding
like a native speaker of
English and today's
phrases are wonderful.
- All right, so let's take a look
at them now in fluency builder.
- Fluency builder.
- So on fluency builder
today, let's take a look at two
different phrases and
let's start with the first one.
She mentioned something
about going cold turkey overnight.
What is that phrase, cold turkey?
- Now this is a very strange phrase, okay?
So first of all, why
would a turkey be cold?
They have lots of feathers.
And second of all, why would it,
what does it have to do with cigarettes?
- Right, so if I say I'm going
cold turkey, what is that?
- So just take this as a phrase.
Don't think about the actual words because
they won't make sense in this context.
What we're talking about
is quitting smoking entirely.
You're not going to cut down.
It means today I'm not gonna smoke
at all and I'm never gonna smoke again.
That means never ever will
I smoke another cigarette.
So it's cold turkey.
- So if I go cold turkey
means I stop doing
something immediately
and suddenly and forever.
- It's highly.
- All right.
- So you can use this
phrase for different habits,
different things that you do, like drinking,
for example, or cutting down on sugar.
But generally we just
say this about cigarettes.
- So it's mostly related to
smoking, going cold turkey.
- Some people like to smoke
less, like one cigarette a day
or one cigarette a week, but going
cold turkey is supposed to be the hardest.
- Right, okay, going cold turkey.
All right, and well, he was explaining
the different negative aspects of smoking.
He said, well, they spend
a fortune on cigarettes
every month and he said,
laws are cracking down.
So if the laws are cracking down,
what is he trying to say there?
- Well, this is actually
a very interesting point
because in America right now, it's
very hard to smoke in public places.
So this means that the government
is trying to stop people from smoking.
So they say, no more
smoking in public places,
no more smoking in restaurants,
no more smoking in bars.
And so this means they're cracking down.
They're making it harder to do something.
So they are becoming more strict.
I think for this phrase, we should listen
to a couple of more examples,
just to make sure we understand it.
- Example one, the police are cracking
down on drunk driving in our city.
- Example two, our school has really
started to crack down on tardiness.
- Example three, the
president has passed a law
that will crack down
possession of legal substances.
- All right, so the government is
cracking down laws are cracking down.
- Yeah, exactly.
So this is an important one
because you read this in the
newspapers as well about
certain laws and police action.
- All right, great.
So I think it's time for us to listen
to this dialogue for one last time.
And then we'll come back and
talk a little bit more about this advice.
- Oh, it smells like an ashtrane here.
- Hi, honey.
What's wrong?
Why do you have that look on your face?
- What's wrong?
I thought we agreed you
were gonna quit smoking.
- No, I said I was gonna cut
down, which is very different.
You can't just expect me
to go cold turkey overnight.
- Look, there are other ways to quit.
You can try the nicotine
patch or nicotine chewing gum.
We spend a fortune on cigarettes every
month and now laws are cracking down
and are allowing smoking
in any public place.
It's not like you can
just light up like before.
- I know, I know.
I really am trying, but I don't
have the willpower to just quit.
I can't fight with the urge
to reach for my pack of
smokes in the morning
with coffee or after lunch.
Please understand.
- Fine, I wanted a voice.
So do you have a problem
with this vice as you call it?
Are you a smoker?
- I'm really not.
I'm the type of person that
could maybe smoke socially,
like if we go out to a bar with drinks,
a social smoker, like they call it, right?
- Yeah, I'm jealous.
But not really, you're a
habitual smoker, right?
- Right, well, I was.
I'm trying to cut down.
So as a habitual smoker,
I often smoked every day.
Sometimes I smoked a lot
and sometimes I smoked less,
but right now I'm in a
period where I'm mostly quit.
- Okay, almost.
Yeah, well, I haven't smoked in a while.
I'm gonna do it's just one cigarette.
- Now, it is interesting
because like we mentioned
laws or cracking down
on where you can smoke,
but also taxes and cigarettes are
becoming much more expensive, right?
- Absolutely, especially
where I'm from in Chicago.
It's easy to spend maybe 10 US dollars
or 12 US dollars on one pack of cigarettes.
- On a pack of cigarettes, imagine that.
So then you have people that can't
help smoking one or two packs a day.
So how much is that a month?
It's just an amazing amount of money.
- That's a dollar as well.
And I have to say though, a lot of my friends
who used to smoke in America have quit.
So this is maybe working.
- The whole thing of making
cigarettes more expensive.
- Yeah, making them much more expensive.
- Now, another interesting thing
and what I was reading recently is that,
you know, those warnings
that come on cigarette packs.
- Yeah.
- That says, you know, smoking
kale, smoking causes cancer.
Actually, a study has
proven that it's not effective
that people don't mind it or even worry
about the cautions on the cigarette packages.
- Well, as a smoker, I could say that,
yeah, you generally, if
you're gonna smoke a
cigarette, don't look
at the label that much.
You just, you know, you throw it
in your bag and you forget about it.
- But it's actually gotten to the point
where people choose the
cigarette pack based on the picture.
So they're like, oh yeah, give me the one
with the black lungs or give me that one.
- Oh, God.
- Yeah, it's interesting.
So it's not really working, I guess.
We're gonna have to find other ways to
make people more conscious about this vise.
- We said, mm-hmm.
- But come to our
website at englishpot.com.
Tell us what you think
about this vise smoking.
Is it good?
Is it bad?
Are you a habitual smoker
or just a social smoker?
- Yeah, we also have
lots of great stuff tools
for you on our website
and expansion sentences
and all that stuff that helps
you continue your studies
outside of, well, the car or your house.
So check it out.
Let us know what you
think, and until next time.
- All right, we'll see you there.
- Bye. - Bye.
(upbeat music)